撑着点  瑞克  已经快到了
C'mon, Rick. We're -- We're almost there.
别管我  莫蒂  这是唯一的方法
Ugh, leave me, Morty. It's the only way.
什么
Wha-- Were -- Wha-- Were we --
我们是刀锋战士吗
Were we Blades in that one?
真他妈的酷
That's fucking tight.
撑着点
Just stay with me.
我好怕  莫蒂
I'm -- I'm scared, Morty.
我能看到结局了
I can see the end.
我太傻了
I'm a silly man.
我就是个小傻子
I'm a silly small man.
很抱歉把你扯进来
I'm -- I'm sorry I got you into this.
让我来解决这个问题吧
Then how about I get us outta this?
-喂  -杰西卡
-Hello?  -Hey, Jessica.
我是跟你同校的莫蒂
I-It's Morty. From school.
莫蒂  你好吗
Oh, hey, Morty. What's up?
我只是想说  你很棒
Um, I just want to say that you're really great.
我知道我们每次都把握不好时机
I know the timing never really worked out with us,
但你真的很棒  我好想更了解你
but you're really great and I wish I got to know you better.
还真是突然
Oh, I mean -- That's a lot.
对  抱歉  我只是
Oh, uh, yeah, sorry, I guess I just --
-不  你该早点说的  -什么
No, I just wish you said it sooner.  -Wh-What?
没错  紧张有时候其实很自私
Yeah, I mean, being nervous is sort of selfish sometimes, y'know?
-维生系统故障  -对  有道理
-Life support systems failing.  -Yeah, that's a great point.
你今晚有事吗
Well, what are you doing tonight?
-今晚  -对  想不想一起看电影之类的
-Tonight?  -Yeah. Do you, like, want to watch a movie or something?
好  今晚  没问题
Um, yeah. Tonight. Sounds great.
糟了  糟了
Holy shit. Holy shit.
拜托  拜托
Come on, come on!
-我们在哪  -到家了  瑞克
-Where are we?  -We're home, Rick.
我降落在了海上
I-I landed us in the ocean.
什么海  地球上的海吗
The ocean?! The ocean on Earth?!
-对  应该是  -该死
-Uh, yeah, I-I guess so.  -Oh, shit.
完蛋了  我们得离开
Holy shit. We have to go. We have to go
他妈的马上离开
We have to go right fucking now.
-什么  -你碰到海了
-What?  -You touched the ocean, Morty.
-为什么不能  -他妈的
-What's the big   ---Oh, fuck. Shit.
-怎么了  -该死
-What?  -Shit.
理查德 你亵渎了
Richard! You have desecrated the sacred treaty
海陆神圣条约
betwixt land and sea.
现在准备承受死敌宁波先生
Now face the wrath of your once and eternal foe --
的怒火吧
Mr. Nimbus!
抱歉  他是谁
Sorry. Who is that?
我的死敌
My nemesis.
-什么  -我的死敌  满意了吗
-What?  -My fucking nemesis, okay?
好吧  但他叫什么
Okay, but what was his name again?
-我是宁波先生  -他会一直讲
I am Mr. Nimbus!  -He's gonna say that a lot.
瑞克和莫蒂
第五季  第一集
等等  到底是谁要来
W-Wait, so who is coming over again?
-他说是他的死敌  -瑞克有死敌吗
He said his nemesis?  -Rick has a nemesis?
-好像是  -他提过那个人吗
I guess. Has hementioned him before?
我才要问你吧  我都没听说过
I-I was gonna ask you. First I'm hearing it.
他是谁  魔术师吗
Who is he? Like a magic guy?
瑞克是科学家  他是魔术师
Rick's science and he's magic?
他应该算鱼
He's like a-a fish?
-一条鱼  -他不是鱼
-A fish.  -He's not a fish.
他是宁波先生  他是海王兼混蛋
He's Mr. Nimbus. He's king of the ocean and he's a piece of shit.
你满意了吗  莫蒂
Are you happy, Morty?
碰到海开心吗
Are you happy you touched the ocean?
他随时都会到
He's gonna be here any minute.
来帮我做准备
Just help me smooth this over
否则他一定会造成更多麻烦
or this guy's gonna become more trouble than he's worth.
我今晚无法帮你太多  瑞克
Um, hey, I don't know how much I can help out tonight, Rick.
杰西卡要来跟我
Jessica's coming over j-just to, like,
一起看电影
watch a movie or something,
但这是很棒的一步
but y'know, t-t-that's a good step.
或许会有好的发展也说不定
That's a solid step to something, y'know?
真的没人在乎你下面  莫蒂
Truly nobody cares about your dick, Morty.
你越快面对现实越好
The sooner you learn that, the better.
你不想我得到幸福
I think you just don't want me happy
想要继续使唤我
'cause then I'll stop doing your crazy chores.
相信我  你搞出那场海洋闹剧
Trust me, after that ocean fuck-up,
你别想多做任何事
you don't get to do anything crazy.
我一边假装
While I bullshit my way
和宁波谈和平条约时
through this peace summit treaty with Nimbus,
夏茉会潜入马里亚纳海沟
Summer is gonna dive into the Marianas Trench
地球上环境最恶劣的区域之一
寻找赋予他力量的
to recover the forbidden shell
神奇贝壳
that gives him his power
因为夏茉值得信任
because Summer can be trusted.
我们来甜蜜蜜
Let's lick tits.
这是个谐音
-好  什么  -我不喜欢
-Okay, what?  -I don't love that.
那是自然
Of course you don't,
因为你们没有性生活
'cause you guys aren't getting any.
其实我们最近
Actually, your father and I
非常性积极
have been very sex-positive lately.
王医师建议我们多多尝试
Dr. Wong suggested we experiment.
我们最近会一起看小电影
We've been watching pornography. Together.
-恶熏  -我不想从海里回来了
Gross! I might never come back from the ocean.
你得低调点  我的宝
Oh, you'll have to tone it down, babe.
这些凡人承受不了
The squares can't handle it.
你们的牙齿里都有自杀胶囊
There are suicide capsules in all of your teeth.
可以用一下
Do what you want with that.
莫蒂  你负责处理酒
C'mon, Morty. You're on booze duty.
好了  宁波只喝高级货
Okay, Nimbus only drinks the good shit.
所以把这酒丢进去
So just toss this whale-ass ocean-wine in here
放个几世纪
and age it up a few centuries.
在里面时间比较快吗
So time moves faster in there?
像纳尼亚一样吗
I-I-Is it like a Narnia thing?
《纳尼亚传奇》中的地名
我不是信上帝的海狸  莫蒂
I'm not a beaver who believes in Jesus Christ, Morty.
《纳尼亚传奇》
但确实就像纳尼亚那样
But yeah, it's pretty much a Narnia thing.
-好吧  但杰西卡  -你只负责端酒
-Okay, but Jessica  -All you have to do is bring wine, Morty.
-我拜托过你什么吗  -你
-When do I ask you for anything?  -When do you --
我好几年没完整上过一周课了
I haven't been to a full week of school in years!
我什么都不会  这是为了什么
I don't know shit! And for what?
你到底有多少敌人
How many enemies do you have to have?
为什么老喜欢起冲突
Why is everything a fight with you?
你要早点看清
You might want to learn this early, Morty.
-人生充满了冲突  -跟宁波先生吗
-Life is a fight.  -With Mr. Nimbus?
你在笑我吗
Are you makin' fun of me?
宁波先生是冷血下体杀手  莫蒂
Mr. Nimbus is an ice-cold dick killer, Morty.
我们走  那是他的魔法海洋号角
Okay, let's go. That's his magic ocean horn.
他是宁波先生吗
Is that Mr. Nimbus?
-宁波  -理查德
-Nimbus.  -Richard.
你脸色真差
You look like ass.
速战速决吧
Let's get this over with.
抱歉  就是他吗
I'm sorry. This is the guy?
-杰瑞  -等等  不
-Jerry.  -Hold on. No.
你是上过星球的人
I've seen you fuck a planet,
竟然怕他
and this is the guy you're afraid of?
我喜欢这个  瑞克
I like this one, Rick.
他很健全且狂野
He is unbroken. Untamed.
或许我们应该把牵绳拉紧一点
Perhaps he could use a firmer grip upon his leash.
好  够了  我要报警了
Okay, that's enough. I'm calling the police.
-没问题  -杰瑞
-Go ahead.  -Jerry.
-我真的会  -我能控制警察
-I will! Good.  -I control them.
-什么  -能控制警察  杰瑞
-Excuse me?  -He controls police, Jerry.
对  我如果会相信就太蠢了
Right, that tracks. In Dumb World.
警察
Police?
有个淫荡海男在我家门口
A strange horny ocean man is on my lawn.
这应该不重要
Well, I don't see how that's relevant,
但我们是白人
but we're white.
不许动  不许动
Freeze! Freeze! Freeze! Freeze!
打架
Fight.
做爱
Fuck.
离开  我们走
Flee. Let's get outta here.
-来吧  理查德  -他怎么
-Shall we, Richard?  -Okay, but how did he --
天啊  杰瑞  他是宁波先生  他能控制警察
Jesus Christ, Jerry. He's Mr. Nimbus. He controls the police!
你们好  是我走错地方了吗
Um, hello? Am I in the right place?
我刚刚看到一群警察在做爱
I just saw a bunch of cops having sex with each other?
杰西卡  你好
Hi! Jessica! Hi!
对  你没走错地方
Yeah, yup, y-you're in the right spot.
各位  这是杰西卡
Uh, everyone, th-this is Jessica.
他们是我家人  这位是
This is everybody. Uh, this is --
-我是宁波先生  -宁波  进来
-I am Mr. Nimbus.  -Jesus, Nimbus, just get inside.
莫蒂  去拿酒
Morty, grab the wine.
好  等一下
Yeah, in a minute.
进来吧  杰西卡
C-C'mon, Jessica.
让开
Stand aside.
除非你们配得上宁波
Unless you are worthy of Nimbus.
如果你指的是那个意思
If that means what I think it means,
我可以告诉你  我们会一起看片
I'll have you know, we watch porn together.
天啊  宁波先生对你们点头了
Wow, okay! Looks like you guys just got the nod.
点头咋了
The nod?
宁波先生直觉很准
Mr. Nimbus has a sense for these things.
你们应该是性积极的夫妇吧
I take it you're a sex-positive couple?
对  非常积极
Oh, yeah. Very much so.
我们会一起看片
We watch porn together. Great!
很好  那我就帮你们登记三人行
I'll mark you down as eligible for a threeway.
这是相关资料
Here's all the information you'll need.
海王想跟我们三人行
The king of the ocean wants to have a threesome with us?
决定权在你们
Totally optional.
不过机会难得  我保证  我很嫉妒你们
But a remarkable option to have, I assure you. Very jealous.
最后一页有表单
There's a form on the last page
请填写收礼物篮的地址
so we know where to send the gift basket.
竟然有这种事
So that just happened.
你好像不排斥
You don't sound upset about it.
你也是
Neither do you.
天啊  我们真的遇到这种事了
Oh, my God. Is this happening? To us?
我以为这种事只会在纽约或HBO上发生
I thought this only happened in New York or on HBO.
王医师一向都是对的
Dr. Wong hasn't been wrong yet.
没错
You're right.
这就是她想要我们做的事
This is exactly what she was talking about.
你可以当自己家
So, uh, yeah. J-Just make yourself comfortable.
选一部电影或是一起看
Y'know, ch-choose a movie or -- or we can watch
跨维度有线电视
some interdimensional cable if you want.
请继续收看任天堂69
We now return to "Nintendo 69."
任天堂  你在干嘛
Nintendo, oh, what are you doing to me?
任天堂
Oh, Nintendo, oh, Nin--
或者我们也可以看
Or we can watch whatever, y'know.
你想看的东西
Wh-Whatever you're into.
莫蒂  你是不是要负责拿酒
Morty, did I hear you're getting wine?
对  我得端酒给宁波先生
Yeah, I gotta get some wine for Mr. Nimbus.
有多的吗
Got any extra?
当然
Oh. Uh, yeah.
-我可以拿来给你喝  -太好了
-Yeah, yeah, I'll go get some, just for you.  -Cool.
快点回来
Hurry back.
看来你好像需要帮忙
Looks like you could use a hand.
对  太好了
Oh, hey! Yeah, th-th-that'd be great.
-没问题  -小蹄  吃晚餐了
-No problem.  -Hoovy? Dinner's ready!
我马上回来  宝贝
Be right there, sugar hoof!
我先帮年轻人把这些
Just helping this young man through a portal
放了好几十年的酒
with that crate full of alcohol
给搬过去
that's been here for decades.
谢了  小蹄  谢谢你的帮忙
Hey, thanks, Hoovy. I-I really appreciate that.
有个女生来我家  我很喜欢她
I-I got a girl over, and I really, really like her.
-我只是很紧张  -我懂
-I-I'm just nervous.  -Oh, I know that feeling.
我刚开始跟波娃交往时
When I first started seeing Bova,
我满脑子都担心自己会搞砸
I could only think about all the ways I was gonna mess it up.
-后来怎么办的  -我搞砸了
-So what'd you do?  -Oh, I messed it up.
但我找到了能接纳我这点的人
But I found the one who loves me for that.
谢谢  我需要你的鼓励
Thanks. I-I really needed to hear that.
-来  拿一瓶走吧  -不用了
-Here, -t-take one of these.  -Oh, you don't have to.
不  我坚持  祝你今天愉快  小蹄
No, I-I want to. You have a good day, Hoovy.
祝你跟那个女生玩得开心
You have a great time with that lady up there.
-放轻松  -没问题
-Just relax.  -Will do!
波娃
Bova?
你为什么离开我们  爸爸
Why did you leave us, Father?
贾费  你什么时候出生的
Japheth? When were you born?
我向妈妈发过誓  只要遇到你
I swore to Mother if I ever met you,
就会为她复仇
I'd avenge her.
不是我的错
It wasn't my fault.
那是谁的错  是谁
Whose, then? Whose?!
从魔法门来的那个男孩
The boy from the magic door.
我们来讨论条约内容吧
Shall we discuss terms?
好  没问题  内容
Yeah, fine. Whatever. Terms.
如下  第一条  我是海王
Term number one -- I am King of the Ocean.
我拉屎的地方  继续
The place I shit? Go ahead.
第二条  别在海里拉屎
Term number two -- Stop shitting in the ocean.
我听不懂
No idea what you're talking about.
真好喝  再来一瓶
Delicious. Another.
我其实想拿这瓶
Oh, uh, well, I-I was thinking of using this one for --
莫蒂  快给他  天啊
Morty, just give him the bottle. God damn.
继续
Another!
莫蒂  拿到酒了吗
Morty, you get the wine?
杰西卡  抱歉
Hey, Jessica. Um, yeah, sorry.
我正要回去拿
I just -- just going back to get it.
你不是刚去了
Oh. I thought you already went.
对  我刚才有点事
I did! I just -- just got a little busy.
我现在再去一次
Going right now, again!
你先准备电影
You go ahead and fire up that movie!
没关系  我等你回来
That's okay. I'll wait for you.
天啊天啊天啊
Holy shit, holy shit, holy shit, holy shit!
我等你好久了
I've been waiting for you.
你是小蹄  对吧
Oh, wow. Hoovy, right?
别说他的名字
Never say his name!
天啊
Jesus Christ!
为什么每个老人都这么壮
Why -- Why is every old guy super jacked?
抱歉  我很抱歉
Sorry! I'm sorry!
我只是要拿酒  抱歉  住手
I-I just need the wine! I'm sorry! Stop it!
我要杀了你
Fucking kill you!
好吧  算了
Ow! Okay, screw this!
知道吗
You know what?
-是你  -对  去死吧小蹄
-You!  -Yeah, fuck you, Hoovy!
爸爸
Father?
就是他  我就说他会再来  天啊
It's him! I told you he'd come back! Holy shit.
好吧  但他十秒钟前还没这么老
Okay, look, he wasn't old like 10 seconds ago.
你这个混蛋
Ow! Mother fucker!
对不起  爸爸  我们应该相信你的
I'm sorry, Father. I'm sorry we never believed.
他还会回来的
He'll come back.
阻止他
Stop him.
爸爸  我们干嘛要守门
Papa, why do we guard the gate?
因为黑暗之子总有一天会再回来
Because one day, the dark child shall return.
而我们会做好准备
And we will be ready.
好吃
Delicious.
负责端酒的人呢  我渴死了
Where is your wine boy, Richard? I thirst.
他去拿了  别这样吃贝奈特饼
He's getting it. Stop eating beignets like that.
一种法式无孔甜甜圈
"参与者若因高潮而死
"Participant voids all liability
不得求偿"
in the event of death by orgasm?"
我们真的要这样做吗
Are we really ready to open things this wide?
如果变得尴尬呢
What if it gets weird?
如果我爱上他呢
I fall in love with him?
不  该死
No, no, no, no, no. Damn it!
怎么回事
What was that?
你又在搞鬼吗  理查德
Another scheme of yours, Richard?
我知道你有阴谋
I know you're planning something.
没什么  失陪一下  好吗
It's nothing. Will you excuse me, please?
搞什么鬼  酒在哪里
What the fuck is going on? Where's the wine?
爸爸刚刚在发春  害我摔破了
Dad was horny and I dropped it.
真不敢相信你竟然搞砸了
God, I can't -- I can't believe you're fucking this up.
我没搞砸  刚刚有个人
I'm not fucking it up! There was a guy in the thing and --
你每次都一堆借口
There's always a guy in a thing!
让宁波等太久可是会没命的
Land dwellers do not keep Nimbus waiting and live.
我马上过去  该死
Be right out! Goddammit.
你把我搞得像在演《欢乐一家亲》
Do you see this whisper kitchen "Frasier" bullshit
美国喜剧
懂吗  莫蒂  快去拿酒
you're making me do? Morty, just get the wine.
贝丝和杰瑞  别想跟宁波做爱
Beth and Jerry, stop trying to fuck Nimbus.
-是他提议的  -不会是在这里
-Well, we wouldn't do it here.  -I'll have you know he propositioned us.
他对任何人都这样提议
He propositions everybody!
杰西卡  杰西卡
Hey, hey, hey, Jessica.
-怎么了  -你好像很忙
-W-What's up?  -Seems like you're busy.
不  我只是有点小麻烦
No, no, no! I ran into a little trouble.
但我马上就要去拿酒来了
But -- But -- But I'll go get that wine right now.
但你已经这样说过两次了吧
But you said were going to get it like twice already.
没错  我现在真的要去拿了
I-I-I was and I-I'm getting it right now.
天啊  是他
Holy shit, it's him!
真是的  你们还要我怎样
God damn it! What do you want me to say?!
我很抱歉
I-I'm sorry!
我们总算打败他了
We finally beat him.
但还是要保持警觉
But let's always remain vigilant
世事难料
because you never know.
他或许还会再来
He might be back one day.
好吧  纳尼亚  来吧
Okay, Narnia! Let's go.
放马过来
Let's fucking go!
结束了  那男孩不会再回来了
It is over. The boy is not coming back.
他一定会的
He always comes back.
你害我们赔上了人生
You have wasted our lives,
还有未来  就为个虚构故事
our very futures, on a fantasy!
-一个谎言  -我确实看到了
-A lie!  -I know what I saw.
你什么都没看到
You saw nothing!
愚蠢的孩子
You are a foolish boy!
勇于看见真相的人才会被骂蠢
Those called fools are the only ones brave enough to see the truth.
告诉我  父亲
Tell me, Father.
我还很蠢吗
Am I a fool now?
我出生于这些石块的制造地
I was born in the pits that made these stones.
我花很久时间建造这座谎言圣殿
I lost my years building a temple to a lie.
所以我就把说谎当成我的能力
So I made lies my power.
能力其实就是我们...
And what is power but a lie we --
天啊  是真的
Oh, shit, he's real!
他是真的  我错了
He's real! I was wrong!
我搞错了  神是真的
I was so wrong! God is real!
服务真棒  我会给很多小费
Wow. Impeccable service. Big tip.
我比较喜欢另一个
I liked your other one more.
他叫什么  凯尔吗
What was his name? Kyle?
-什么  -没事
-What?  -Nothing.
我们可以快点签约吗
Can we just sign this thing and go?
-杰西卡  真抱歉  -没关系
-Jessica, -I-I'm so sorry.  -I mean, it's fine.
你才离开几分钟而已
You were only gone like a couple minutes.
莫蒂  你还好吗
Morty, are you okay?
抱歉  杰西卡
I'm -- I'm sorry, Jessica.
我们每次都搞砸  对吧
We just never seem to get it right, do we?
是啊  的确如此
No, I guess we don't.
但我很高兴你打电话给我
But I'm glad you called me.
我们可以重来  这次别再搞砸了
Maybe we can start over, get it right this time.
好  我也这样想
Yeah. I'd -- I'd like that.
谢谢你拿酒来
Thanks for bringing the wine.
绝对值得
Totally worth it.
需要开瓶器吗
Do we need an opener?
我去拿
Oh. I'll -- I'll -- I'll go get it.
我很喜欢签约  要签了吗
I do so love to sign upon the dotted line.
-没错  -天啊
-Shall we?  -Jesus Christ, yes.
你的证人是谁
And who is your witness?
我的证人是这只鱿鱼
My witness is the squid.
你很喜欢海洋世界主题  对吧
Really proud of this SeaWorld theme, aren't you?
快去找证人  别怪到我头上
Hey, just get a witness, man. Don't make this about me.
或许他没有值得
Or perhaps Richard has no one
托付生命的人
with whom he can trust his life.
除了我以外没有人
Who truly knows him.
-真正了解他  -好吧
-Save me.  -Fine!
我去找人  天啊
I'll get someone. Oh, my God.
莫蒂  过来  我需要你做件事
Morty! C'mere. I need you for some bullshit.
瑞克  我达成你的每一项要求了
Look, Rick, I've done everything you've asked.
我能好好陪我女朋友吗
Now can I just have some time with my girlfriend?
女朋友
Your girlfriend?
她不是...我们接吻了
I mean, she's not -- we kissed,
但我想慢慢来
but I'm just trying to take it slow.
不可以太操之过急  懂吗
You gotta give these things time to breathe, y'know?
你知道你为什么特别吗  亚当
Do you know why you're special, Adam?
-因为我是旅行者  -对
-Because I am The Traveler?  -Yes.
你会穿越那扇门
You will be the one to pass through the door.
终结我们的痛苦
to end our pain.
那我的痛苦呢  妈妈
But, Mother, what about my pain?
你的痛苦会解放我们
Your pain shall set us free.
该开始了
It is time to begin.
再来
Again.
Again!
-你还没准备好  -拜托  妈妈
-You are not ready.  -Please, Mother --
你以为他会放过你吗
Do you think he will show you mercy?
看他对我们做了什么
Like he did to us?
再来
Again!
有人需要什么吗
Does anyone need anything?
-天啊  -别评断我们
-Holy shit!  -Don't judge.
我们夫妻要一起成长
We're growing as a couple! Aah!
为什么发生在我身上
Why is this happening to me?!
为了未来
For the future!
你竟然想暗杀宁波
You dare assassinate Nimbus?
抱歉  等等  他是谁
Sorry. Wait. Who -- Who is that?
还没轮到你  老兄
Get in line, pal!
真是浪费
Such a waste.
妈妈
M-Mother?
杰西卡
Jessica!
你就是非碰海不可
You just had to touch the ocean.
闭嘴
Aaah! Shut up!
我没时间...
There isn't time to --
全都搞砸了  被你搞砸了
It's all fucked! And you fucked it!
你来太早了
You're early.
这是哪里
W-What is this place?
是终点  也是起点
The end. But also a beginning.
-每个终点都是起点  对吧  -后退
-Isn't every end a beginning?  -Stay back!
别跟我说些日舞科幻鬼话
I don't want your stripped down Sundance sci-fi bullshit.
-杰西卡在哪  -杰西卡
-Where's Jessica?  -Jessica.
那是她的名字对吧  谢了  莫蒂
That was her name, wasn't it? Thank you, Morty.
我都忘记了  对了
I had forgotten. Oh, right.
你可以用这个
You'll be needing this.
酿酒
For the wine.
妈的  我们骗到他了
Oh, shit, we got him!
你敢相信他被这些鬼话骗了吗
Can you believe he bought that fucking tree bullshit?
我们他妈的骗到他了
We fucking got him!
非常好
Very well.
想跟亚特兰蒂斯开战  就顺你意
If you seek war with Atlantis, you shall have it.
我之前上美人鱼时
Oh, I've already been to war with Atlantis
就已经开战了
when I D-Day'd that Mermaid Puss!
我就知道是你
I knew that was you!
准备离场车队
Prepare my exit parade!
跟你爱的干燥陆地道别吧
Say goodbye to your precious dry land!
这里很快就会变湿  超级湿
For soon it will be wet! Wet!
全球变暖已经弄湿陆地了  混蛋
Yeah, global warming is already doing that, asshole.
尽管来吧  让我们变得更湿一点
But sure, yeah, go for it. Make us slightly more wet!
你把我当笑话
Am I a joke to you?
对  你他妈的就是
Yes, you are a fucking joke!
你烂透了  你一直都很烂
You fucking suck! You've always sucked!
知道我们为什么好几年没打仗吗
Y-Y-Y know why we haven't fought in years?
因为你很可笑
'Cause you're an embarrassment to me
我不再需要你了
and I don't need you anymore.
我再不靠别人
I don't need anybody.
我一直在跟任天堂做爱
All I do is eat ass and 69 Nintendos, bro.
-每一天  -或许你会讨厌我
-Every day.  -Or maybe you hate me
是因为只有我知道你变得多惨
because I am the only man to see how far you have fallen.
我曾经害怕你  尊敬你
I used to fear you. Respect you.
但我现在只会可怜
Now all that's left is pity --
你这可悲的酒鬼
for a sad, drunk shell of a man
你不敢承认自己有多寂寞
too afraid to see how alone he truly is.
如果戴安还活着  她会怎么...
If Diane were alive today, what would she think --
瑞克已故妻子
少跟我讲另一个时空的背景故事
Don't fucking establish canonical backstory with me, you Red Lob--
很好  你醒了
Oh, good. You're awake.
我只是拿了些酒
I just took some wine!
我都道歉了
I said I was sorry.
你们是有什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with you people?!
我已经想了好几世纪了
I have been asking that for centuries.
他们创造我是为了研究你  莫蒂
I was created to study you, Morty, to know you.
但我越仔细看
But the closer I looked,
就越不认识自己
the more I do not recognize myself.
好吧  我其实没时间...
Uh, yeah, man, I really don't have time for --
如果没有你  我们会是什么人
I have often wondered who would we be without you, Morty?
我们除了恨意还有什么
Are we anything beyond our hatred?
她来的时候
And when she came,
我以为她会是答案
I thought she would be the answer.
冻结在时间内  永远沉睡
Frozen in time. Forever asleep.
我们不懂她的意义
We could not understand her purpose,
就把她藏起来
so we hid her away.
我们为什么要隐瞒所害怕的真相
Why do we always hide the truths we fear?
我才不在乎
I don't give a shit, nerd!
-放了她  -我干嘛要复制生殖器
-Let her go!  -Why -- Why did I clone myself genitals?
-我不在乎  混蛋  快点  -混蛋
-I don't care, bitch! Do it!   -Ooh! Asshole!
我就是混蛋
Yeah, guess I am an asshole!
有时候就得当混蛋
Y'know, sometimes you gotta be an asshole!
这是我外公教我的
My grandpa taught me that!
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay, okay, fine!
-莫蒂  -杰西卡
-Morty?  -Hey, Jessica.
你一定睡得很熟  对吧
Wow. Must've been some nap, huh?
我不知道这些东西是什么
I-Is that ooze or -- I'm not sure what to call it.
看起来像分泌物
It l-l-looks like ooze.
好了  我们之后再聊
Okay. W-We can catch up later.
什么...
What the --
瑞克  瑞克
Rick! Rick!
-死龙虾  -瑞克
-...obster motherfucker. Rick!
-管他的  我在干嘛  -救命
Screw this. What am I even doing?  -Help!
你要去哪
Where are you?
快回来  我会把陆地变湿
Come back here. I'm going to make the land wet!
我倒想亲眼看看
Y'know what, I'd love to see it.
放马过来  随便你做什么
Do it! God, do anything!
-但别再拿我当借口了  -瑞克
-Just don't use me as an excuse anymore!  -Rick!
天啊  真火爆
That was intense.
你压力很大吗
You look stressed.
-我们签了文件  -我得走了
-We signed the paperwork.  -I must go.
你们有我们的电话
Well, your people have our number!
那只海星不是说有礼物篮吗
Your starfish mentioned some kind of basket?
-莫蒂  停下  -今天不行
-Jesus, Morty. Stop!  -No, no! Not today!
你就不能有一天...
Can't you go one day without --You don't get to --
-什么...  -我搞砸了  好吗
-What the  -I fucked it up, okay?
没关系  莫蒂  你就是这样
It's okay, Morty. That's what you do.
现在让我来拯救一切  带你们回家
Now lemme Deus Ex Machina this shit and let's go home.
天啊  为什么大家都变成机械鸟了
God, why does everyone go Cyber-Punk Bird?
真他妈无趣
So fuckin' hack.
妈的
Oh, shit.
还真酷
Well, that's cool.
好吧  我们好像要完蛋了
Okay, we might be a little fucked.
你以为我会让你孤独死去吗  理查德
Did you think I would let you die alone, Richard?
我是宁波先生
I am Mr. Nimbus!
你还有时间看电影吗
You -- You still got time for that movie?
有
Yes.
时间
Time.
我有很多时间
I had nothing but time.
无尽的时间
Endless time.
一开始只有疯狂
At first, it was madness.
然后是启示
Then enlightenment.
然后又是疯狂
Then madness again.
但这或许是好事
But perhaps it was a gift.
我看到了时间的生命
I could see the life of time.
正当我见证着时间
And as I watched the life of time
悲惨那一面时
in all its fleeting, terrible light,
我陷入了沉思  我有活过吗
I wondered, had I lived?
我只是其他人故事中的物件吗
Was I just the object in another's story?
我就仅此而已  这点能改变吗
Was that all I ever was? Could I be more?
我有非常多的时间  却没有答案
I had nothing but time and still no answer.
没有意义的时间就像牢笼
Time without purpose is a prison.
我看到了永恒的思想
I have glimpsed into the mind of eternity.
或是神的思想
Perhaps the mind of God.
但我只找到寂静
And found nothing but silence.
我们还是当朋友就好
I think we should just be friends.
好吧
Oh, yeah.
我能理解
I-I-I get that.
我们错过了时机
Guess we missed our moment.
对  但我们都会有
Yes. But there will be more.
其他时机
For both of us.
再见了  莫蒂
Goodbye, Morty.
你好吗
Hey, how's it going?
滚  我是时间之神
Fuck off! I'm a Time-god!
我又跟你一同作战了  理查德
Fighting by your side again, Richard.
-感觉很...  -没错
It was, uh --Yeah.
那就不用签条约了
Then there is no treaty.
我们停战
Because there is no war.
宁波
Aw, Nimbus.
你人真好
That's -- That's really chill of you, man.
理查德
Richard.
你在成为我的宿敌之前
Before you were my greatest enemy,
是我唯一的朋友
you were my only friend.
-外公  我弄到贝壳了  -该死
-Grandpa, I got the shell!  -Shit.
-听着  宁波  -王八蛋  叛徒
Okay, Nimbus, look.  -You son of a bitch!
拿武器来  莫蒂
Betrayal! My weapons, Morty!
被我用光了
I-I-I used them all! Grandpa!
外公  我该怎么办
Wait, Grandpa, what do I do?
贝壳在我这里  我要吹吗
I have the shell. Should I blow it?
我直接吹好了
Is that -- I'm -- I'm just gonna blow it!
不要吹  砸烂它
Don't blow it! Destroy the horn!
夏茉  你搞什么
What the hell, Summer?!
要把贝壳砸烂
You were supposed to destroy the horn!
我怎么会知道
How was I supposed to know that?
警察
Police!
把这人渣关进牢里
Take this piece of shit to jail.
我说过了
I told, ugh, I told you.
他是冷血下体杀手
He's an ice-cold dick killer!
宁波
Nimbus!
等等  他怎么...
Wait. So how can he --
天啊  夏茉  他是宁波
Jesus, Summer. He's Mr. Nimbus.
他能控制警察
He controls the police!
杰瑞  太多安全语
Jer, I think more than one safe word
就失去意义了
sort of defeats the point.
我只是希望
I know, I just wanna make sure
我们能有机会喊停
we have every opportunity to stop.
但我很期待
Super excited about it though.
我也很期待
Me too, so excited.
杰瑞  我们是真的想这么做吗
Jerry, are we doing this because we both want this?
还是我们以为对方想这么做
Or because it's what we think the other one wants?
我只是想证明我很爱你  愿意为你
I just wanted to prove that I love you so much
做这种事  我也是
I would do this for you! Same!
我们拿完奖品就走吧
Let's take that prize and get out
不要犯下大错
before we make a huge mistake.
后悔了
Getting cold feet?
不
No.
-别告诉瑞克  -他不会懂的
-Please don't tell Rick.  -He wouldn't understand.
会  他会懂的
Yes, he would.